<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: RubyConf | David Chelimsky]]></title>
  <link href="http://dchelimsky.github.io/blog/categories/rubyconf/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dchelimsky.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-18T19:54:30+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dchelimsky.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[get off (the couch) with me]]></title>
    <link href="http://dchelimsky.github.io/blog/2009/09/25/get-off-the-couch-with-me/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-25T19:46:06+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dchelimsky.github.io/blog/2009/09/25/get-off-the-couch-with-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As <a href="http://chadfowler.com/">Chad Fowler</a> points out in his blog about the <a href="http://chadfowler.com/2009/9/25/unofficial-rubyconf-5k">unofficial rubyconf 5k</a>, the whole idea was born out of a conversation he and I were having about his new running habit, and how I&rsquo;d been trying to get back into running for years and never had the right motivation. Well, there is little motivation to get back into it than helping to organize a 5k!</p>

<p>I just started back a little over a week ago and, this week, started the <a href="http://www.coolrunning.com/engine/2/2_3/181.shtml">couch to 5k</a> schedule. For those of you who have never run, or haven&rsquo;t run in years, this schedule is absolutely fantastic.</p>

<p>It starts off with with alternating intervals of jogging for a minute and walking for 1.5 minutes for a total of 20 minutes. I immediately found that I was pushing much harder than normal for me during the 1 minute jogs, and after the 20 minutes I felt great! One week into this and I&rsquo;m already jogging 8 minutes (sure, not in a row, but <em>8 minutes</em> the 2nd week off the couch!).</p>

<p>Today I dragged my girlfriend along (she&rsquo;s planning to run a 5k with me on Thanksgiving morning). Flor exercises regularly, but she is <em>not</em> a runner, yet she had no problem keeping up with me for these short intervals.</p>

<p>Of course I&rsquo;m only a week into the schedule, and I&rsquo;m sure it will get more challenging as the intervals get longer, but I&rsquo;m pretty confident I&rsquo;ll be able to keep up with the gradually increasing intensity.</p>

<p>So I encourage any of you who are attending RubyConf (or JRubyConf) to join us. We&rsquo;ll have a website up with information and registration in a few weeks, but today is the day to start training! See you at the starting line!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
